# **OPJOT SINGH NIJJAR**

### Front-End Web Developer

@ opjot.n@gmail.com

**4** 647-999-9804

% WWW.OPJOT.COM

in LINKEDIN

O GITHUB

### **SKILLS**

HTML5 CSS3

SASS

JavaScript

JQuery

Github

**Email Dev** 

Responsive Design

Accessibility

### **ABOUT**

A front-end developer with experience in HTML5, CSS3, & JavaScript. My background in Marketing, Customer Service, & Sales allows me to understand user needs & wants, so I can provide a great user experience on my apps & web pages. I am always in a learning mindset to better my skills and continue growth.

React

### **PROJECTS**

### Willow | HTML & SASS |

A multi-page personal website for Willow including an about page, blog and contact form. Different styling techniques are used to achieve a desirable look and media queries for responsiveness.

### Juno Bingo | ¡Query & SASS HTML|

A two player game where you have to match the numbers on your card to the numbers being called. This game uses multiple functions to generate random numbers for different parts of the game, along with different conditional loops.

### Quick Flick Picker | React & Firebase & Axios |

A web app to help you decide which movie you should watch. I worked with setting up Firebase and accessing the API using Axios. By using multiple components and branches on GitHub we were able to collaborate and create this project.

## **EDUCATION**

Immersive Web Development Certificate / Accelerated JavaScript / Web Dev 101

Juno College of Technology - Toronto, ON

May 2019 - March 2020

Bachelor's of Business Commerce & Post Graduate Certificate (Accounting)

York University - Toronto, ON

🗎 Sept. 2012 - April 2017 / Sept. 2018 - April 2019

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Surface Installer & Office Assistant - Everplay Installations Inc.

May 2016 - Nov. 2019

Brampton, ON

- Responsible for calculating quantity of materials required for jobs & shipping materials to job sites.
- Prepared designs and mixed materials on site for the installation of rubber surfacing in parks and playgrounds.

#### Marketing & CRM Associate - Elite Mouldings Inc.

May 2018 - Sept. 2018

North York, ON

- Worked alongside clients to assess and provide optimal solutions for their need, while also handling inquiries and product disputes.
- Consistently met customer service goals the supervisors set by effectively managing my time and providing excellent service to clients.

### **Benefits Specialist - American Income Life Insurance Company**

max Dec. 2017 - May 2018

Oakville, ON

- Worked independently with the company's childsafe program to consult and provide insurance products that aid in estate planning to clients.
- Responsible for advising existing and prospective clients on financial investments in one on one meetings.

# **COMMUNITY WORK**

### Core Member

Sikh Initiative (Toronto Singhs Camp)

## 2015 - Current

A Canadian NPO focused on teaching Sikh values & enriching the Sikh Spirit.

#### Volunteer

### Khalsa Aid (Canada)

## 2018 - Current

An international NGO with the aim to provide humanitarian aid around the world.